Let's add the code now to our app.
さぁ、アプリにコードをつけましょう。
The base price is composed of two parts.
基本料金は2つの要素から成り立ちます。
The price of the coffee, which is $5 plus any toppings.
コーヒーの料金$5とトッピングの料金です。
So $1 for whip cream, or $2 for chocolate.
トッピングは生クリームが$1で、 チョコが$2
That will brings us to the total order price.
これで合計金額が計算されます。
Let's calculate the price for a sample order,
サンプルのオーダーで 料金を計算してみましょう。
where the user wants 3 cups of coffee with whipped cream, like this.
このようにコーヒーを3杯に 生クリームをトッピングした場合、
The goal of this course is not to test your math skills so let's walk through
ここではあなたの算数の能力を 試すのが目的ではないので
the calculation together to make sure that you understand it.
一緒に計算して、 きちんと理解できるようにしましょう。
The real goal will be for you to translate this logic into code.
本当の目的は、 この論理をコード化することです。
In this sample order the user wants 3 cups of coffee with whipped cream,
サンプルオーダーでは生クリーム付きの コーヒーを3杯注文しています。
like this.
この図のように
First, we can start off by calculating the base price of 1 cup of coffee.
まずは、1杯分の基本料金を計算します。
We start with $5 for the coffee cup plus $1 for the whipped cream topping.
コーヒー1杯が$5で、 生クリームのトッピングが$1なので
That brings us to $6 per cup.
1杯$6となります。
Then, we need to find the total order price.
次に合計金額を計算しなければなりません。
Since the user ordered 3 cups of coffee, we multiply $6 per cup times 3 cups.
ユーザーは3杯注文したので、 $6かける3杯となり
That equals $18 total for the whole order.
合計金額は$18になります。
In this sample order, we have 2 cups of coffee and
別のサンプルオーダーでは、コーヒー2杯に
each cup has whipped cream topping and chocolate topping, like this and this.
生クリームとチョコをトッピングしています。 この図のように。
First, we calculate the base price of 1 cup.
まず、1杯分の料金を計算します。
A cup of coffee costs $5, and then we add $1 for
コーヒー1杯が$5、生クリームが$1で
whipped cream and $2 for chocolate.
チョコが$2です。
That brings us to a total of 5, 6, 7, 8, $8 per cup.
全てを足すと、5、6、7、8。 1杯は$8です。
Then we find the total order price since the user ordered 2 cups of coffee.
それでは合計金額を計算しましょう。 ユーザーはコーヒーを2杯注文したので、
We take the base price of $8 per cup of coffee times 2 cups and
1杯分の料金$8を2杯でかけると
that brings us to $16 total for the whole order.
合計金額は$16となります。
This is what our app should look like.
これがアプリの見た目です。
We can enter in a name,
名前を入力して
choose a whipped cream topping and then change the quantity to 3.
生クリームをトッピングに選んで、 個数を3にします。
If we hit the Order button, we expect the price to change to $18.
ORDERボタンを押すと、 料金は$18になるはずです。
This is exactly what we calculated earlier by hand.
この数字は先ほど私たちが 計算したものと一致します。
If I add the chocolate topping, change the quantity to 2.
トッピングにチョコを追加して、 個数を2にすると
Then the total price becomes $16,
合計金額は$16になりました。
also just like we calculated where we have $8 per cup of coffee.
コーヒー1杯を$8として 計算した時の数字に一致します。
Now, go ahead and plan out the steps that you need to do in order to add this
それでは、この機能をアプリに 追加するために必要なことを
functionality to our app.
リストして計画立てましょう。
I wrote down the price of the toppings here for reference.
参考までに、 ここにトッピングの料金を書き出しました。
And here's a screen shot of what the app should look like
そしてこれがアプリ画面の スクリーンショットです。
with the adjusted price here.
ここには更新された金額もあります。
After you've planned out the steps then go ahead and implement this in your app.
手順を書き出したら、 早速アプリに実装しましょう。
Then, can you tell me what method did you end up modifying?
でき上がったら、どのメソッドを 修正したか教えてください。